<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Allen Akinkunle | Data Science, Machine Learning</title>
 <link href="http://allenkunle.me/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <id>http://allenkunle.me</id>
 <updated>2020-11-08T15:40:52+00:00</updated>
 <author>
   <name>Allen Akinkunle</name>
   <uri>http://www.allenkunle.me</uri>
   <email>hello@allenkunle.me</email>
 </author>

 

 <entry>
   <title>The Bias-Variance Decomposition Demystified</title>
   <link href="http://allenkunle.me/bias-variance-decomposition"/>
   <id>http://allenkunle.me/bias-variance-decomposition</id>
   <updated>2020-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;The generalisation error of a machine learning algorithm measures how accurately the learning algorithm is able to predict the outcome of new data, unseen during training. The bias-variance decomposition shows the generalisation error as the sum of three terms: bias, variance, and the irreducible error.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class=&quot;math&quot;&gt; $$...</content>
 </entry>

 

 <entry>
   <title>Deriving Machine Learning Cost Functions using Maximum Likelihood Estimation (MLE) - Part II</title>
   <link href="http://allenkunle.me/deriving-ml-cost-functions-part2"/>
   <id>http://allenkunle.me/deriving-ml-cost-functions-part2</id>
   <updated>2019-03-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;/deriving-ml-cost-functions-part1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Part I&lt;/a&gt; of this article, we introduced Maximum Likelihood Estimation (MLE), Likelihood function, and derived Mean Squared Error (MSE) using Maximum likelihood estimation. In this article, we will use Maximum likelihood estimation to derive Cross-Entropy cost function, which is commonly used for binary classification problems.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;...</content>
 </entry>

 

 <entry>
   <title>Deriving Machine Learning Cost Functions using Maximum Likelihood Estimation (MLE) - Part I</title>
   <link href="http://allenkunle.me/deriving-ml-cost-functions-part1"/>
   <id>http://allenkunle.me/deriving-ml-cost-functions-part1</id>
   <updated>2019-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;In supervised machine learning, cost functions are used to measure a trained model’s performance. The most commonly used cost function for regression is the Mean Squared Error (MSE), and Cross Entropy for binary classification problems. For many people, the reasons for choosing these cost functions are not at...</content>
 </entry>

 

 <entry>
   <title>dplyr-style Data Manipulation with Pipes in Python</title>
   <link href="http://allenkunle.me/dplyr-style-data-manipulation-in-python"/>
   <id>http://allenkunle.me/dplyr-style-data-manipulation-in-python</id>
   <updated>2018-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I often use R’s &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dplyr&lt;/code&gt; package for exploratory data analysis and data manipulation. In addition to providing a consistent set of functions that one can use to solve the most common data manipulation problems, dplyr also allows one to write elegant, chainable data manipulation code using pipes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Now,...</content>
 </entry>

 

 <entry>
   <title>Exploratory Analysis of the Washington's Post Police Shooting dataset using R and Plotly</title>
   <link href="http://allenkunle.me/exploratory-analysis-police-shooting"/>
   <id>http://allenkunle.me/exploratory-analysis-police-shooting</id>
   <updated>2016-07-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/national/police-shootings-2016/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Washington Post&lt;/a&gt; has been compiling a database of fatal shootings in the United States by police officers in the line of duty since January 1, 2015. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/washingtonpost/data-police-shootings&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;dataset&lt;/a&gt; contains information such as the date and the state in which the killing occurred, the age, gender...</content>
 </entry>

 

</feed>